Privacy Policy
==============

How do we handle your privacy, which services do we use, which rights do you have?

Your privacy is important to us. Psono follows some fundamental principles:

* We do not ask for any information that we do not really need
* We do not share your information with anyone except to comply with the German law, protect our rights and develop our product.

Your personal data is processed by us only in accordance with the German data privacy law. The following passages describes the type and purpose of the use of the gathered personal data. This privacy policy only applies to “psono.com” and no other linked domains.

**Contact Details:**

If you are looking to contact the body that is responsible for the data privacy then please reach out to:

esaqa GmbH  
Tiergartenstr. 13  
91247 Vorra  
Germany  
  
Managing Director: Sascha Pfeiffer  
Commercial Register: Nuremberg Registry Court HRB 37978  
USt-IdNr.: DE333156173  
E-mail: support@esaqa.com  

**Personal Data**

Any data (name, address, billing information, IP-address, …) is only used to fulfill the service and without a legal basis or your explicit consent, not given to any third parties.

Psono.com collects personal-identifying information like for example the IP address while using our service, to ensure the service availability and to protect your account. Psono may use that information for statistical analysis and may display this anonymized statistical analysis publicly or provide it to others.

Account holders in addition must specify some additional information during registration, like for example their e-mail address. That information is used to prevent service disruptions and to inform users about security relevant information and provide services like password reset or to contact the user in case of new invoices or failed payments.

**What User Data We Collect**

When you visit the website, we may collect the following data:

* Your IP address
    
* Your browser / OS and version
    
* Your language
    
* Date and time of the request
    
* Requested resource / website
    
* Transfered data
    
* Status code of the request
    
* Website who refered you
    
* Your contact information and email address
    
* Data profile regarding your online behavior on our website

If you order a product or a service we collect in addition the following data:

* Name
    
* Address
    
* Payment information

**Why We Collect Your Data**

We are collecting your data for several reasons:

* To better understand your needs.
    
* To improve our services and products.
    
* To protect our system against attacks and fraud
    
* To be able to invoice services proper

**Your rights**

You have the followinng rights about your personal data:

* Right to be informed
    
* Right of access
    
* Right to rectification
    
* Right to erasure
    
* Right to restrict processing
    
* Right to data portability
    
* Right to object
    
* Rights related to automated decision making including profiling

You further have the right to make a complaint to the ICO or another supervisory authority

Services
--------

Services that we use and that store and handle your data

**Browser Storage**

For technical reason (login, sessions, ...) we are using browser storage (e.g. cookies, local storage, ...), which stores data in your browser.

**Google Analytics**

This website uses Google Analytics (GA) (by Google Inc), to analyse customer behaviour on the website. GA for that reason uses cookies to identify and track users and user behaviour. GA offers the possibility to opt out of this data collection by installing a browser plug-in here: [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en) Psono uses the server side tag manager, which truncate IPs before processing them to prevent direct associations to persons.

**Brevo**

This website is using Brevo (formerly Sendinblue) as a service to handle all email traffic, including newsletter, registration emails, support emails and potential security notifications. Whenever a user uses our service or subscribes to our newsletter, the email address is handled by Brevo in accordance with [Brevo's terms of use](https://www.brevo.com/legal/termsofuse/) .

**Freshdesk**

This website uses Freshdesk to handle support requests. Whenever you are opening a new ticket, via email or support form it will be processes by Freshdesk including all information that you may provide in the process (IP, email address, all data of your support request, ...).

**Cloudflare**

Psono is using Cloudflare to protect it's server from DDoS attacks, offer reduced load times for users and decrease the general server load. Requests are proxied by servers that are closest to the user. An overview of Cloudflares data privacy commitment can be found here in [Cloudflare's privacy policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/)

**Google Cloud Platform**

This website's backend services are hosted by Google on the Google Cloud Platform. Google itself has the highest standards of privacy. Yet as the platform provider, Google has access to all information that the application itself has access to (e.g. your ip, email address, browser information, ...).  
More information about how Google handles informations and what measures have been applied can be found for example in Google's [Terms of Service](https://cloud.google.com/terms/) and Google's [Data Processing and Security Terms](https://cloud.google.com/terms/data-processing-terms)

Psono may update its privacy statement from time to time and we encourage everyone to check regularly. It has last been updated May 20th, 2024.

Pages
-----

Our Information
---------------

Contact
-------

Address
-------

* esaqa GmbH
* Tiergartenstr. 13
* 91247 Vorra
* Germany

Copyright © 2020 esaqa GmbH
